Finding Aid for Arthur J. Tuttle Papers 1849-1958
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Financial Materials
  - Income tax returns
    - 1942 (Box 105)
    - 1943 (Box 105)
    - 1944 (Box 105)
  - Cottage 1936-1941 (Box 105)
  - Orchards re. spray residue 1933 (Box 105)
  - Ford Lake Sub. No. 1 1926-1932 (Box 105)
  - Sharecropping contracts for Leslie farm 1912-1916 (Box 106)
  - Deeds and mortgages for Leslie property 1861-1900 (Box 106)
  - Index cards, Tuttle's recurring bills (Box 106)
    (Club memberships, subscriptions, etc.)
  - Tuttle's expense books while student at University of Michigan 1888-1893 (Box 106)
- Miscellaneous biographical materials
  The Miscellaneous biographical materials series (.5 linear feet) contains Tuttle's obituaries, bar memberships, and bills he proposed in the Michigan Legislature, among many other items.
  - Statistical Record Hon. Arthur J. Tuttle, Judge, U.S. District Court, Eastern District of Michigan Jan 1 1932 Reported Cases Only (shows name of case, subject, subsequent history) (Box 106)
  - AJT Admission to Michigan Bar June 5, 1895 (Box 106)
  - AJT Admission to Bar for 6th Circuit November 24, 1903 (Box 106)
  - AJT Admission to Bar of Washtenaw County June 1895 (Box 106)
  - A.J. Tuttle's diary 1881 (Box 106)
    (Aged 13)
  - A.J. Tuttle school papers 1880s (Box 106)
  - A.J. Tuttle's autograph book 1878 (Box 106)
  - Bills introduced in Michigan Legislature circa 1907 (Box 106)
  - Printed legislative materials circa 1907 (Box 106)
  - Journal, European Honeymoon 1903 (Box 106)
  - Columns, European Honeymoon 1903 (Box 106)
  - American Legal News Featuring A.J. Tuttle, 1918 (Box 106)
  - Miscellaneous. biographical material 1888-1944 (Box 106)
    (Poems by A.J. Tuttle)
  - Obituary and tributes to A.J. Tuttle 1933-1944, 2 folders (Box 106)
  - Golf scores undated (Box 106)
  - Blueprint map, Turtle Lake Club, Hillman, Michigan undated (Box 106)
- Tuttle family materials
  The Tuttle family materials series (1.3 linear feet) includes two subseries: papers related to Arthur Tuttle's immediate family, his wife, Jessie Stewart Tuttle, daughters, Ruth and Esther Tuttle, and sister, Grace Tuttle Annis and papers related to John J. Tuttle, Arthur's grandfather. John J. Tuttle was school director and supervisor of Leslie Township, Ingham County, county coroner and justice of the peace, and agent for the Cayuga Chief Manufacturing Company, a maker of farm equipment, and an important figure in the founding of the Michigan Republican Party.
  - Arthur J. Tuttle family
    - Esther Tuttle's Autograph Book 1921 (Box 106)
    - Ruth Tuttle's Diary 1913 (Box 106)
    - Ruth Tuttle's Diary 1917 (Box 106)
    - Ruth Tuttle's Northern High English Notebook circa 1920 (Box 106)
    - Dance Card, Junior Hop 1924 (Box 106)
    - Jessie Stewart Tuttle, Passbook (Box 106)
    - Jessie Stewart Tuttle House Account (Box 106)
    - Grace Tuttle Annis papers 1896-1958 (Box 106)
    - Ruth Tuttle's first case 1929 (Box 106)
    - Esther Tuttle: Assistant Attorney General (Box 106)
    - Esther and Ruth Tuttle Scrapbook, Ruth Tuttle Teacher Certificate, Ruth Tuttle Bar Admission (Box 106)
    - Family correspondence 1888-1943, 3 folders (Box 106)
  - John J. Tuttle Papers 1849-1895
    - Tuttle family genealogical and biographical material (Box 107)
    - Correspondence 1861-1895, 22 folders (Box 107)
    - Cayuga Chief Manufacturing Company, Auburn, New York (Box 107)
    - Farm equipment miscellanea (Box 107)
    - Certificates (Box 107)
    - Will 1881 (Box 107)
    - Miscellanea (Box 107)
    - School District no. 2, Leslie Township 1849-1858 (Box 107)
    - First National Bank, Leslie Township miscellanea (Box 107)
    - Leslie Township miscellanea (Box 107)
    - Ingham County Agricultural Society miscellanea (Box 107)
    - Ingham County Pioneer Society miscellanea (Box 107)
    - Farmers Mutual Fire Insurance Company, Ingham County miscellanea (Box 107)
    - Michigan Republican party miscellanea (Box 107)
    - Unidentified and fragmentary (Box 107)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual materials series (1 linear foot) includes photographs and albums. They contain images of Tuttle family members, friends, vacations, farms, and law offices.
  - Photographs
    - Annis, Grace Tuttle--early photos (sister of J.J. Tuttle) (Box 108)
      (folder 1 and UAx)
    - Annis, Grace Tuttle--later photos (Box 108)
      (folder 2)
    - Birthday party for A.J. Tuttle circa 1938 (Box 108)
      (folder 3)
    - Camp Bryn Afon, Rhinelander (Box 108)
      (folder 4)
    - Cyclone, Leslie, Mich. 1916 (Box 108)
      (folder 5)
    - Family, individuals (Box 108)
      (folder 6)
    - Family groups (Box 108)
      (folder 7 and UAx)
    - Friends (Box 108)
      (folder 8)
    - Groups, miscellaneous (Box 108)
      (folder 9)
    - Homes, farms (Box 108)
      (folder 10)
    - Hunting (Box 108)
      (folder 10a)
    - Leslie, Mich. (Box 108)
      (includes Election of 1896 photo
      (folder 10b)
    - Lyons, Mich. (Box 108)
      includes Grand River flood photos
      (folder 10c)
    - Miner, Jack: Bird Sanctuary (Box 108)
      (folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 108)
      includes law office photo
      (folder 12)
    - Orchard and Tuttle Park, Leslie, Mich. 1923 (Box 108)
      (folder 13)
    - Presidents (T. Roosevelt, W.H. Taft, H. Hoover) (Box 108)
      (folder 14)
    - Stewart family (Box 108)
      (folder 15)
    - Summer home, Pleasant Lake (Box 108)
      (folder 16)
    - Tuttle, Arthur J.--early photos (Box 108)
      (folder 17 and UAx)
    - Tuttle, Arthur J.--portraits, snapshots (Box 108)
      (folder 18 and UAm)
    - Tuttle, Jennie Stewart (wife of A.J. Tuttle) circa 1895-1912 (Box 108)
      (folder 19 and UAm)
    - Tuttle, Jennie Stewart, drawing (Box 108)
      (folder 19a)
    - Tuttle, John J. (Box 108)
      (UAx)
    - Tuttle, Julia (Box 108)
    - Tuttle, Ruth and Esther (daughters of A.J. Tuttle) (Box 108)
      (folder 20)
    - Tuttle, Ogden Valorous (father of A.J. Tuttle) 1842-1916 (Box 108)
      (folder 21 and UAm)
  - Albums
    - Camp Bryn Afon, Rhinelander, Wisconsin (Box 108)
      (Summer camp photos of girls riding horses, swimming, playing basketball, etc.)
    - Esther Louise Tuttle and Ruth Beatrice Tuttle baby album (Box 108)
    - Jessie Beatrice Stewart Tuttle bereavement album (Box 108)
    - Ruth Beatrice Tuttle bound application to Vassar College (Box 108)